Andrea McCarthy

983 Maple Ave, New York. NY 10031 andreamccarthy@exannple.com (123) 456-7891

Awa rd-winning storyteller and expert data scientist with a passion for sharing tech and science innovation with the world. Comfortable interviewing renowned scientists and tech industry leaders. Has strong graphic design skills and can write and produce infographics.

Education

Bachelor of Arts in Journalism and Bachelor of Science in Data Science

University of Southern California Los Angeles, CA August 2014 - May 2018

Key Skills

- Applied Statistics
- Coding (Java, Python, HTML)
- Critical Thinking
- Infographics
- Research
- Storytelling

Professional Experience

Science and Technology Reporter

Popular Mechanics, New York, NY | January 2020 - Present

- Won third place for science feature from the National Association of Science Writers
- ♦ Collaborate with subject matter experts to translate complex clinical data into everyday Language and engaging news
- ♦ Research and implement tactics for reaching and engaging Popular Mechanics audiences via multiple channels, resulting in record-breaking online traffic
- Educate and supervise as many as four student interns each semester regarding the inner workings of a science news publication
- Partner with graphic design and photo departments to bring science stories to life

Technology Journalist

The Verge, Silicon Valley, CA I September 2018 - December 2020

- Interviewed key players at prominent technology businesses who drive decision-making, growth, and innovation
- Developed profile stories on many of the tech gurus behind the most impactful innovations of our time
- Used storytelling skills to communicate the importance of advancements currently being made in the tech industry
- Shadowed more experienced technology journalists and helped fact-check and copy edit their work